Erwin Chargaff Papers 1929-1992 Mss.B.C37
American Philosophical Society
- Series III. Works by Chargaff, 1929-1989; 15.5 linear feet
  - Patterns of Cellular Controls Operating in Bacteriophage Reproduction. I. Effect of 5-Fluorouracil on the Multiplication of Several Coliphages, 5/12; Chargaff, Fred Goodman and Jussi J. Saukkonen (Box 87)
  - Patterns of Cellular Controls Operating in Bacteriophage Reproduction. II. Effect of 5-Fluorouracil on Metabolic Events in Bacteria Infected with Coliphage T2rt, 5/12; Chargaff, Jussi J. Saukkonen and Fred Goodman (Box 87)
  - The Pentose Nucleic Acid of Azotobacter Vinelandii, [1956]; Chargaff and Anna Lombard (Box 87)
  - Perigos da Intromissao Genética, 5/30; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 87)
    In Portuguese
  - Phosphatide Composition in Different Liver Cell Fractions, 5/4; Chargaff and Celia Levine (Box 87)
  - Physical and Chemical Properties of the Apurinic Acid of Calf Thymus, [1953]; Chargaff and Christoph Tamm (Box 87)
  - Physico-Chemical and Metabolic Studies of the Soluble Ribonucleic Acid of Rat Liver Cell, [1959?]; Chargaff and Harold T. Shigeura (Box 87)
    See also Ser.III, The Soluble Ribonucleic Acid of Rat
  - Die Pigmente der Sarcina Lutea, [1932]; Chargaff and Joseph Dieryck (Box 87)
  - Plans for Future Research, [193-]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 87)
  - Polynucleotide Synthetase of E. Coli: An Enzyme Complex Having Polynucleotide Phosphorylase as Apoenzyme, 5/31; Chargaff and Yiannis G. Stavrianopoulos (Box 87)
    - Folder 1, 5/31 (Box 87)
    - Folder 2, 5/31 (Box 87)
  - Polyribophosphate, an Immunologically Active Type-Specific Substance, [1952]; Chargaff, Stephen Zamenhof, Grace Leidy, Patricia L. Fitzgerald, and Hattie E. Alexander (Box 87)
  - Polyribophosphate, the Type-Specific Substance of Hemophilus Influenzae, Grace Leidy, Patricia L. Fitzgerald, and Hattie E. Alexander, [1953]; Chargaff and Stephen Zamenhof, Grace Leidy, Patricia L. Fitzgerald, and Hattie. Alexander (Box 87)
  - Ein Polysaccharid aus den Lipoiden der Tuberkelbakterien, [1930]; Chargaff and R.J. Anderson (Box 88)
  - A Polysaccharide from Diphtheria Bacteria, 5 Sep. 1939; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 88)
  - Preface to a Grammar of Biology, [1971]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 88)
  - The Problem of Nucleotide Sequence in Deoxyribonucleic Acids, 1960-1961; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 88)
    See also Ser.III, Essays on Nucleic Acids
    -See also Ser.VI, The Problem of Nucleotide Sequence in Deoxyribonucleic Acids
  - The Problem of Sequence Analysis in Nucleic Acids, 5/12; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 88)
    Jesup Lecture IV
  - The Problem of Specificity and the Carriers of Biological Information, 5/12; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 88)
    Jesup Lecture I
  - The Problem of the Primary Structure of the Deoxyribonucleic Acids, Oct. 1961; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 88)
    See also Ser.I, Pontifica Academia Scientiarum
  - Procedure for the Study of Certain Enzymes in Minute Amounts and Its Application to the Investigation of Cytosine Deaminase, [1948]; Chargaff and Jacob Kream (Box 88)
  - Procedures for the Microestimation of Nitrogenous Phosphatide Constituents, [1951]; Chargaff and Celia Levine (Box 88)
    See also Ser.III, Survey of the Distribution of Nitrogenous Constituents in Beef Brain Phosphatides
    -See also Oversized
    - Folder 1, [1951] (Box 88)
    - Folder 2, [1951] (Box 88)
  - Profitable Wonders: A Few Thoughts on Nucleic Acid Research, [1975]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 88)
  - Program of Work on Blood Coagulation, [193-]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 88)
  - Progress Report Covering Work on the Chemistry and Physiology of Thromboplastic Lipids and Related Substances--Progress reports, 1953-1955; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 88)
  - Properties of a Purified Sialidase and Its Action on Brain Mucolipid, 5/13; Chargaff, Abraham Rosenberg and Calderon Howe (Box 89)
  - Proposal Concerning the Creation of a Laboratory for Chemical Cell Research, 28 Feb. 1949; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 89)
  - The Protamine Salts of Phosphatides, with Remarks on the Problem of Lipoproteins, [1938]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 89)
  - Protoplasts of E. Coli as Sources and Acceptors of Deoxypentose Nucleic Acid: Rehabilitation of a Deficient Mutant, 5/10; Chargaff, Herbert M. Schulman and Herman S. Shapiro (Box 89)
  - Pulse-Labeled Ribonucleic Acid of Rhodopseudomonas Spheroides in the Presence and Absence of Massive Catalase Formation, 5/15; Chargaff, Anne M. Haywood and Ernest D. Gray (Box 89)
  - Purification and Properties of a Nucleoside Phosphotransferase from Carrot, [1967]; Chargaff and Elinor F. Brunngraber (Box 89)
  - Purification and Properties of Ribonuclease H of Calf Thymus, [1973]; Chargaff and Yiannis G. Stavrianopoulos (Box 89)
  - Purification of the Desoxypentose Nucleic Acid of Hemophilus Influenzae Having Transforming Activity, 5/4; Chargaff, Stephen Zamenhof, Grace Leidy, Patricia L. Fitzgerald, and Hattie E. Alexander (Box 89)
  - A Purine Polyribonucleotide Synthetase from Escherichia Coli, [1973]; Chargaff and Roberto Milanino (Box 89)
    Some in German and Italian
  - Pyrimidine Nucleotide Sequences in Deoxyribonucleic Acids, 5/14; Chargaff and John H. Spencer (Box 89)
  - A Quick Climb up Mount Olympus [Review of] The Double Helix: A Personal Account of the Discovery of the Structure of DNA by James D. Watson, [1968]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 89)
  - Rapidly Labeled Ribonucleic Acids of Rhodopseudomonas Spheroides Under Varying Conditions of Catalase Synthesis, [1964]; Chargaff, Ernest D. Gray and Anne M. Haywood (Box 89)
    - Folder 1, [1964] (Box 89)
    - Folder 2, [1964] (Box 89)
  - The Reaction Between Cephalin and Hemoglobin, [1939]; Chargaff, Morris Ziff and Bruce M. Hogg (Box 90)
  - Recent Procedures for the Study of Lipoproteins and Lipids, [1951]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 90)
  - Recent Studies on Cellular Lipoproteins, [1949]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 90)
  - Recent Studies on Nucleic Acid Specificity, [1957]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 90)
  - Recent Studies on Ribonucleoproteins and Ribonucleic Acids, Oct. 1956; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 90)
  - Recent Studies on the Polymeric Mucolipids of Nervous Tissue, 5/14; Chargaff, Abraham Rosenberg and Calderon Howe (Box 90)
  - Recent Work on Lipoproteins as Cellular Constituents, [1947]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 90)
  - Reflections on the Art and Science of Doing Research, 6/2; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 90)
  - Regularities and Differences in the Nucleic Acid Field, 7 Sep. 1951; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 90)
  - Regularities in the Composition of Pentose Nucleic Acids, [1954]; Chargaff and David Elson (Box 90)
  - A Reinvestigation of the Cerebroside Deposited in Gaucher's Disease, [1958]; Chargaff and Abraham Rosenberg (Box 90)
  - Relation of Ribonucleic Acid to the Photosynthetic Apparatus in Euglena Gracilis, 5/11; Chargaff and George Brawerman (Box 90)
  - The Relative Speed of Formation of Lecithin and Cephalin in the Body, Apr. 1939; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 90)
  - Remarks on Deoxyribonuclease, 5/8; Chargaff and Herman S. Shapiro (Box 90)
  - Remarks on Nucleic Acid Metabolism, 12 Jan. 1949; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 90)
  - Remarks on Research in the Biological Sciences at the Columbia Medical Center, 6-7 Nov. 1967; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 90)
  - Remarks on Sequence Characteristics of the DNA and Transfer RNA of Yeast, 5/20; Chargaff and Herman S. Shapiro (Box 90)
  - Remarks on the Biochemistry of the Inositols, 5/8; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 90)
  - Remarks on the Knowledge Industry, Chargaff, Erwin (Box 90)
  - Remarks on the Physiological Importance of the Nucleoside Phosphotransferases, [1955]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 90)
  - Remarks on the Role of Lipids in Blood Coagulation, [1948]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 90)
  - A Report on the Problems Which Are Being Actually Investigated, [193-]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 90)
  - Report on Visit to the Biology Division of the Oak Ridge National Laboratory, 9-11 Nov. 1959; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 90)
  - Rhythmic Alterations in the Rate of Synthesis and the Composition of Rapidly Labelled Ribonucleic Acid During the Synchronous Growth of Bacteria, [1964]; Chargaff, Rivka Rudner and Barbara Prokop-Schneider (Box 90)
  - Ribonuclease H of Calf Thymus: Substrate Specificity, Activation, Inhibition, [1976]; Chargaff, Yiannis G. Stavrianopoulos and John D. Karkas (Box 90)
  - Le Rôle des Lipides et des Lipoprotéines dans la Structure Cellulaire, [1948]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 91)
  - Role of Base-Pairing in the Control of an Enzyme Reaction, 19 Dec. 1968; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 91)
  - A Self-Reproducing System Concerned with the Formation of Chloroplasts in Euglena Gracilis, [1960]; Chargaff and George Brawerman (Box 91)
  - The Separation and Characterization of Purines in Minute Amounts of Nucleic Acid Hydrolysates, [1947]; Chargaff and Ernst Vischer (Box 91)
  - The Separation and Estimation of Ribonucleotides in Minute Quantities, [1950]; Chargaff, Boris Magasanik, Ernst Vischer, Charlotte Green, Ruth Doniger, and David Elson (Box 91)
  - The Separation and Quantitative Estimation of Purines and Pyrimidines in Minute Amounts, [1948]; Chargaff and Ernst Vischer (Box 91)
  - Separation of B. Subtilis DNA into Complementary Strands. I. Biological Properties, [1968]; Chargaff, Rivka Rudner and John D. Karkas (Box 91)
  - Separation of B. Subtilis DNA into Complementary Strands. II. Template Functions and Composition as Determined by Transcription with RNA Polymerase--John D. Karkas and Rivka Rudner, [1968]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 91)
  - Separation of B. Subtilis DNA into Complementary Strands. III. Direct Analysis, [1968]; Chargaff, Rivka Rudner and John D. Karkas (Box 91)
  - Separation of Calf Thymus Deoxyribonucleic Acid into Fractions of Different Composition, [1953]; Chargaff, Charles F. Crampton and Rakoma Lipshitz (Box 91)
  - The Separation of Choline and Ethanolamine, 4/19; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 91)
  - Separation of Desoxypentose and Pentose Nucleic Acids, [1951]; Chargaff and Stephen Zamenhof (Box 91)
  - Separation of Microbial Deoxyribonucleic Acids into Complementary Strands, [1969]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 91)
  - Separation of Nucleoside Phosphotransferase and Phosphatase Activities, 5/9; Chargaff and Marvin Tunis (Box 91)
  - Sequential Arrangement of 5-Bromouracil as a Tool for the Study of the Replication of Deoxyribonucleic Acid, 5/15; Chargaff and Rivka Rudner (Box 92)
  - Serious Questions: An ABC of Skeptical Reflections, [198-]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 92)
    - Folder 1, [198-] (Box 92)
    - Folder 2, [198-] (Box 92)
    - Folder 3, [198-] (Box 92)
  - Severe Distortion by 5-Bromouracil of the Sequence Characteristics of a Bacterial Deoxyribonucleic Acid, [1960]; Chargaff and Herman S. Shapiro (Box 92)
  - A Simplified Method for the Purification of Ribonuclease H from Calf Thymus, n.d.; Chargaff and Yiannis G. Stavrianopoulos (Box 92)
  - The Soluble Ribonucleic Acid of Rat Liver Cell, [1959?]; Chargaff and Harold T. Shigeura (Box 92)
    See also Ser.III, Physico-Chemical and Metabolic
  - Some Observations on the Mucolipids of Normal and Tay-Sachs' Disease Brain Tissue, [1959]; Chargaff and Abraham Rosenberg (Box 92)
  - Some Properties of an Unstable E. Coli Ribonucleic Acid, [195-]; Chargaff, Jack Horowitz and Anna Lombard (Box 92)
  - Some Recent Studies on the Composition and Structure of Nucleic Acids, [1951]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 92)
  - Specific Yeast Inhibition by Meso-Inositol of the Colchicine Effect on Rat Fibroblasts, [1951]; Chargaff, Margaret R. Murray and Helena H. de Lam (Box 92)
  - A Specific Polysaccharide from the Bacillus Calmette-Guérin, [1935]; Chargaff and Werner Schaefer (Box 92)
    See also Ser.III, Chemical and Immunological
  - Specific Requirements for the Action of Deoxyribonuclease, [1951]; Chargaff and Christoph Tamm (Box 92)
  - The Stereochemical Specificity of the Oxidation of Cyclitols by Acetobacter Suboxydans, Chargaff, Boris Magasanik and Robert E. Franzl (Box 92)
  - The Stereochemistry of an Enzymatic Reaction: The Oxidation of l-, d-, and epi-Inositol by Acetobacter Suboxydans, [1948]; Chargaff and Boris Magasanik (Box 93)
    - Folder 1 (Box 93)
    - Folder 2 (Box 93)
  - Sterical Hindrance in the Inositol Group, 4/19; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 93)
  - The Stoichiometric Relationship Between Amino-Acid and Nucleotide Residues in a Ribonucleoprotein, 29 Sep. 1956; Chargaff, David Elson and Harold T. Shigeura (Box 93)
  - Structure and Function of Nucleic Acid as Cell Constituents, [1951]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 93)
  - The Structure of a New Cyclohexose Produced from d-Inositol by Biological Oxidation, [1948]; Chargaff and Boris Magasanik (Box 93)
  - Studies of the Dynamics of Ribonucleic Acid Formation, [1958]; Chargaff and Harold T. Shigeura (Box 93)
  - Studies on Inhibition of the Colchicine Effect on MitosisMurray, [1954]; Chargaff and Helena H. Benitez and Margaret R. (Box 93)
  - Studies on Nucleoproteins. I. Dissociation and Reassociation of the Deoxyribonucleohistone of Calf Thymus, [1954]; Chargaff and Charles F. Crampton and Rakoma Lipshitz (Box 93)
  - Studies on Nucleoproteins. II. Fractionation of Deoxyribonucleic Acids Through Fractional Dissociation of Their Complexes with Basic Proteins, [1954]; Chargaff, Charles F. Crampton and Rakoma Lipshitz (Box 93)
    - Folder 1 (Box 93)
    - Folder 2 (Box 94)
  - Studies on Nucleoproteins. III. Deoxyribonucleic Acid Complexes with Basic Polyelectrolytes and Their Fractional Extraction, [1955]; Chargaff, Pnina Spitnik and Rakoma Lipshitz (Box 94)
  - Studies on Nucleoproteins. IV. Preparation of the Deoxyribonucleoprotein and Fractionation of the Deoxyribonucleic Acid of Wheat Germ, 5/8; Chargaff and Rakoma Lipshitz-Weisner (Box 94)
  - Studies on Nucleoproteins. V. Interactions, 1955-1956; Chargaff and Charles F. Crampton and Rakoma Lipshitz (Box 94)
  - Studies on Nucleoproteins. VI. The Deoxyribonucleoprotein and the Deoxyribonucleic Acid of Bovine Tubercle Bacilli, [1958]; Chargaff and Toru Tsumita (Box 94)
  - Studies on the Biosynthesis of RNA in the Presence of 5-Fluorouracil, 5/14; Chargaff and Jack Horowitz (Box 94)
  - Studies on the Chemistry of Blood Coagulation. I. The Measurement of the Inhibition of Blood Clotting. Methods and Units, [1936]; Chargaff, Frederic W. Bancroft and Margaret Stanley-Brown (Box 94)
  - Studies on the Chemistry of Blood Coagulation. II. On the Inhibition of Blood Clotting by Substances of High Molecular Weight, [1936]; Chargaff, Frederic W. Bancroft and Margaret Stanley-Brown (Box 94)
  - Studies on the Chemistry of Blood Coagulation. III. The Chemical Constituents of Blood Platelets and Their Role in Blood Clotting, with Remarks on the Activation of Clotting by Lipids, [1936]; Chargaff, Frederic W. Bancroft and Margaret Stanley-Brown (Box 94)
  - Studies on the Chemistry of Blood Coagulation. IV. Lipid Inhibitors of Blood Clotting Occurring in Mammalian Tissue, [1937]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 94)
  - Studies on the Chemistry of Blood Coagulation. V. Synthetic Cerebroside Sulfuric Acids and Their Action in Blood Clotting, [1937]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 94)
  - Studies on the Chemistry of Blood Coagulation. VI. Studies on the Action of Heparin and Other Anticoagulants. The Influence of Protamine on the Anticoagulant Effect in Vivo, [1937]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 94)
  - Studies on the Chemistry of Blood Coagulation. VII. Protamines and Blood Clotting, [1938]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 95)
  - Studies on the Chemistry of Blood Coagulation. VIII. Isolation of a Lipid Inhibitor of Blood Clotting from the Spleen in a Case of Niemann-Pick's Disease, [1938]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 95)
  - Studies on the Chemistry of Blood Coagulation. IX. The Thromboplastic Protein from Lungs, [1940]; Chargaff and Seymour S. Cohen (Box 95)
  - Studies on the Chemistry of Blood Coagulation. X. The Reaction Between Heparin and the Thromboplastic Factor, [1940]; Chargaff, Morris Ziff and Seymour S. Cohen (Box 95)
  - Studies on the Chemistry of Blood Coagulation. XI. The Mode of Action of Heparin, [1940]; Chargaff and Morris Ziff (Box 95)
  - Studies on the Chemistry of Blood Coagulation. XII. An Electrophoretic Study of the Effect of Anticoagulants on Human Plasma Proteins, with Remarks on the Separation of the Heparin Complement, 4/23; Chargaff, Morris Ziff and Dan H. Moore (Box 95)
  - Studies on the Chemistry of Blood Coagulation. XIII. The Phosphatide Constituents of the Thromboplastic Protein from Lungs, [1941]; Chargaff and Seymour S. Cohen (Box 95)
  - Studies on the Chemistry of Mucolipids: Occurrence of the Long-Chain Base Icosisphingosine, Composition of Fatty Acids, Fractionation Attempts, Chargaff and Nikola Z. Stanacev (Box 95)
    - Folder 1 (Box 95)
    - Folder 2 (Box 95)
  - Studies on the Composition of Nucleic Acids, [1948]; Chargaff and Ernst Vischer (Box 95)
  - Studies on the Composition of Rickettsia Prowazeki, [1944]; Chargaff and Seymour S. Cohen (Box 95)
  - Studies on the Desoxypentose Nuclease of Yeast and Its Specific Cellular Regulation, [1949]; Chargaff and Stephen Zamenhof (Box 96)
  - Studies on the Diversity and the Native State of Desoxypentose Nucleic Acids, [1950]; Chargaff and Stephen Zamenhof (Box 96)
  - Studies on the Dynamics of Chloroplast Formation in Euglena Gracilis, [1963]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 96)
  - Studies on the Fractionation and Composition of Deoxyribonucleic Acids, [1954]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 96)
  - Studies on the Fractionation of Ribonucleic Acid, [1960]; Chargaff and Rakoma Lipshitz-Weisner (Box 96)
  - Studies on the Loss and Restoration of the Transforming Activity of the Deoxyribonucleic Acid of Bacillus Subtilis, [1967]; Chargaff, Rivka Rudner, Hsiang Ju Lin, and Silke E.M. Hoffmann (Box 96)
    - Folder 1 (Box 96)
    - Folder 2 (Box 96)
  - Studies on the Mechanism of Deamination of Serine and Threonine in Biological Systems, [1943]; Chargaff and David B. Sprinson (Box 96)
  - Studies on the Mechanism of the Thromboplastic Effect, [1948]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 96)
  - Studies on the Mucolipids and the Cerebrosides of Chicken Brain During Embryonic Development, 5/16; Chargaff and Owen W. Garrigan (Box 96)
    - Folder 1 (Box 96)
    - Folder 2 (Box 96)
  - Studies on the Nucleoside Phosphotransferase of Carrot. I. Partial Purification of the Nucleoside Phosphotransferase, [1960]; Chargaff and Marvin Tunis (Box 97)
  - Studies on the Nucleoside Phosphotransferase of Carrot. II. Separation of Transferase and Phosphatase Activities, [1960]; Chargaff and Marvin Tunis (Box 97)
  - Studies on the Nucleoside Phosphotransferase of Carrot. III. On the Synthetic Ability of the Transfer Enzyme, 5/12; Chargaff and Marvin Tunis (Box 97)
  - Studies on the Nucleotide Arrangement in Deoxyribonucleic Acids. I. The Relationship Between the Production of Pyrimidine Nucleoside 31, 51, -Disphosphates and Specific Features of Nucleotide Sequence, [1957]; Chargaff and Herman S. Shapiro (Box 97)
  - Studies on the Nucleotide Arrangement in Deoxyribonucleic Acids. II. Differential Analysis of Pyrimidine Nucleotide Distribution as a Method of Characterization, [1957]; Chargaff and Herman S. Shapiro (Box 97)
  - Studies on the Nucleotide Arrangement in Deoxyribonucleic Acids. III. Identification of Methylcitidine Derivatives Among the Acid Degradation Products of Rye Germ DNA, [1960]; Chargaff and Herman S. Shapiro (Box 97)
  - Studies on the Nucleotide Arrangement in Deoxyribonucleic Acids. IV. Patterns of Nucleotide Sequence in the Deoxyribonucleic Acid of Rye Germ and Its Fractions, [1960]; Chargaff and Herman S. Shapiro (Box 97)
  - Studies on the Nucleotide Arrangement in Deoxyribonucleic Acids. V. Pyrimidine Nucleotide Clusters: Isolation and Characterization, [1963]; Chargaff and John H. Spencer (Box 97)
  - Studies on the Nucleotide Arrangement in Deoxyribonucleic Acids. VI. Pyrimidine Nucleotide Clusters: Frequency and Distribution in Several Species of the AT-Type, 5/15; Chargaff and John H. Spencer (Box 97)
  - Studies on the Nucleotide Arrangement in Deoxyribonucleic Acids. VII. Direct Estimation of Pyrimidine Nucleotide Runs, [1963]; Chargaff and Herman S. Shapiro (Box 97)
  - Studies on the Nucleotide Arrangement in Deoxyribonucleic Acids. VIII. A Comparison of Procedures for the Determination of the Frequency of Pyrimidine Nucleotide Runs, [1964]; Chargaff and Herman S. Shapiro (Box 97)
  - Studies on the Nucleotide Arrangement in Deoxyribonucleic Acids. IX. Selective Degradation of Pyrimidine Deoxyribonucleotides, [1964]; Chargaff, Alfred Temperli, Hans Türler, Peter Rüst, and Arlette Danon (Box 98)
  - Studies on the Nucleotide Arrangement in Deoxyribonucleic Acids. X. Frequency and Composition of Pyrimidine Isostichs in Microbial Deoxyribonucleic Acids and in the DNA of E. Coli Phage T3, 5/19; Chargaff, Rivka Rudner and Herman S. Shapiro (Box 98)
    - Folder 1, 5/19 (Box 98)
    - Folder 2, 5/19 (Box 98)
  - Studies on the Nucleotide Arrangement in Deoxyribonucleic Acids. XI. Selective Removal of Cytosine as a Tool for the Study of the Nucleotide Arrangement in Deoxyribonucleic Acid, [1966]; Chargaff and Herman S. Shapiro (Box 98)
  - Studies on the Nucleotide Arrangement in Deoxyribonucleic Acids. XII. Apyrimidinic Acid from Calf Thymus Deoxyribonucleic Acid: Preparation and Properties, [1969]; Chargaff and Hans Türler (Box 98)
  - Studies on the Nucleotide Arrangement in Deoxyribonucleic Acids. XIII. Frequency and Composition of Purine Isostichs in Calf-Thymus Deoxyribonucleic Acid, [1969]; Chargaff, Hans Türler and Jerzy Buchowicz (Box 98)
  - Studies on the Specification of Accessory Biochemical Characters, as Exemplified by the Fatty Acid Patterns of Various Strains of Escherichia Coli, [1965]; Chargaff, John D. Karkas and Hans Türler (Box 99)
    - Folder 1, [1965] (Box 99)
    - Folder 2, [1965] (Box 99)
  - Studies on the Specificity of the Enzymic Synthesis of Polyribonucleotides, [1967]; Chargaff and Florence E. Farber (Box 99)
    - Folder 1, [1967] (Box 99)
    - Folder 2, [1967] (Box 99)
  - Studies on the Stability of Simple Derivatives of Sialic Acid, [1964]; Chargaff and John D. Karkas (Box 99)
  - Studies on the Structure of Ribonucleic Acids, [1951]; Chargaff and Boris Magasanik (Box 99)
  - Studies on Thromboplastic Proteins and Lipids, [1954]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 99)
  - A Study of a Mucolipide from Ox Brain, [1958]; Chargaff and Abraham Rosenberg (Box 99)
    - Folder 1, [1958] (Box 99)
    - Folder 2, [1958] (Box 99)
  - A Study of Beta-Hydroxy-a-Keto Acids, Chargaff, Erwin (Box 100)
  - A Study of Inositol-Containing Lipides, [1954]; Chargaff and John N. Hawthorne (Box 100)
  - A Study of Lipoproteins, [1942]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 100)
  - A Study of Ribonuclease H of Calf Thymus: Substrate Specificity, Activation, Inhibition, Chargaff, Erwin (Box 100)
    See Ser.III, Ribonuclease H of Calf Thymus...
  - Study of Some Constituents of Vitamin B12, [1950]; Chargaff, Celia Levine, Charlotte Green, and Jacob Kream (Box 100)
  - A Study of the 21-0-Methylribonucleotide Constituents of Yeast Transfer RNA, Chargaff, Erwin (Box 100)
    See Ser.III, On the Bias of the Distribution of the 21-0-
  - A Study of the Nitrogenous Constituents of Tissue Phosphatides, [1942]; Chargaff, Morris Ziff and David Rittenberg (Box 100)
  - A Study of the Spleen in a Case of Niemann-Pick Disease, [1939]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 100)
  - Sur les Pigments Caroténoides de Deux Bactéries Acidorésistantes, Chargaff, Erwin (Box 100)
    See Ser.III, Ueber die Carotinoiden Pigmente Zweier
  - Survey of DNA Polymerase Activity During the Early Development of Drosophila Melanogaster, [1973]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 100)
  - Survey of the Distribution of Nitrogenous Constituents in Beef Brain Phosphatides, [1951]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 100)
  - Sweepings from the Corridors of Power. [Review of] The Double Helix. A Personal Account of the Discovery of the Structure of DNA by James D. Watson, [1968]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 100)
  - Synthesis of 2-Methyl-L, 4-Naphthquinone-8-Sulfonic Acid, [1943]; Chargaff and Aaron Bendich (Box 100)